seattlechildrens.org 2011-05-15

# Privacy Policy | Seattle Children's Hospital

Seattle Children's (Children's) is committed to providing its users with an Internet experience that respects and protects their personal privacy choices and concerns.

We have created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the website www.seattlechildrens.org.

This site contains links to other sites. Children's is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

## Your Privacy Rights

Children's is committed to keeping your child or teen's health information private and confidential. Our Notice of Privacy Practices tells how we use your child's health information and lists reasons why we would need to give this information to others.

View or print our **Notice of Privacy Practices** (PDF English | Russian") | Spanish") | Vietnamese")). You can also pick up a copy of the brochure at the following locations:

  * Any clinic's registration desk
  * The Emergency Department 
  * Admitting 
  * The Family Resource Center 

Questions? Contact the Privacy Office.

## Traffic Data Collected

When you use our site, we collect anonymous information. Anonymous information is information about how you use our site (such as places visited and searches performed).

Anonymous information also includes the domain names and/or IP addresses of browsers that visit our site, time of day the site was visited and other non-personally identifiable information. Anonymous information is information that is not tied to any individual, but helps to characterize Children's users to improve our services.

We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer our website. We use cookies to identify returning visitors, so that they do not have to reenter a password whenever they return to our site.

## Personal Information Collected

Our site uses an order form for customers to request information, products and services. We collect a visitor's contact information (such as an e-mail address) and financial information (such as an account or credit card numbers) in the online gift store and the Ways to Help sections. This information is used to fulfill orders and process payments or donations.

The customer's contact information is also used to get in touch with the visitor when necessary. For example, we might have a question about the processing of an order. If a user so requests, we may use the contact information to send the user additional information about Children's.

Users may opt out of receiving future mailings (see the choice/opt-out section below). Our online surveys ask visitors for contact information (like their e-mail address). The customer's contact information is used to contact the visitor when necessary. Again, users may opt out of receiving future mailings (see the choice/opt-out section below).

## Secure Area

When you register for access to the secured content area for Medical Staff and Healthcare Professionals, we ask for information such as your name, title, practice name and address, e-mail address, phone number and role.

This information is used to confirm your identity and the appropriateness of your request to access sensitive healthcare information and to improve your experience by presenting you with appropriate content.

Once you register and sign in, you are not anonymous to us. In the event of abuse, this information may be used to revoke your existing access to this and other Children's systems.

You may request to have your account for accessing the secured section of the Healthcare Professionals area removed by sending an e-mail including your name, practice and user ID to us.

The personally identifiable information we collect is not used for any purposes other than order fulfillment, processing of donations, dissemination of information and authentication to the secured content on this website.

It is not disclosed to anyone other than Children's and its partners, contractors and agents, unless we must do so to comply with a court order or other legal process, or we must do so to protect our rights or property.

Please note that Seattle Children's will not intentionally share the contents of any e-mail or form submitted through this site with any third party. However, due to the nature of electronic communications, we cannot and do not provide assurances that the contents will not become known or accessible to third parties.

WE URGE YOU NOT TO PROVIDE ANY CONFIDENTIAL INFORMATION ABOUT YOU, YOUR HEALTH OR YOUR PATIENTS TO US VIA ELECTRONIC COMMUNICATION UNLESS WE INDICATE THE FORM HAS BEEN SECURED.

## Electronic Bulletin

When you receive the electronic Bulletin, Children's maintains information about you including your name, position and role at Children's, your medical staff membership status and your e-mail address.

This information is used to support your ability to select the content areas in which you are interested, to collect traffic data about the Bulletin and to help Children's to direct information to appropriate groups of providers.

The personally identifiable information we collect is not used for any purposes other than those listed above and will not be not disclosed to anyone other than Children's and its partners, contractors and agents, unless necessary to comply with a court order or other legal process, or to protect the rights or property interests of Children's.

You may request to be removed from the electronic Bulletin e-mail list by clicking on "unsubscribe" at the end of the electronic Bulletin.

## Public Forums

This site makes limited use of chat rooms, forums, message boards and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.

## Security

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. Information is stored on secure servers. Access to change or edit content/information is restricted to those authorized by Children's to do so.

## Choice/Opt-Out

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt out of or opt into receiving communications from us and our partners at the point at which we request information about the visitor.

A user who does not wish to receive future communications should e-mail us.

## Correct/Update

A user who wishes to modify or correct information previously provided should e-mail us.

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or your dealings with this website, you may contact:

Web Services Manager  
Seattle Children's  
PO Box 50020 / S-217  
Seattle, WA 98145  
E-mail Web Services 

Children's Privacy Office  
Mailstop A-4902  
PO Box 5371  
Seattle, WA 98145-5005  
206-987-1200  
866-987-2000, extension 7-1200 (toll free)  

## Updates and Changes to Privacy Policy

We reserve the right, at any time, to add to, change, update or modify this privacy policy, simply by posting such change, update or modification on the site.

Any such change, update or modification will be effectively immediately upon posting.
